[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"1. A letter to this thinker objects to his invocation of the Scholastic notion of a rock’s weight since his own mechanistic physics denied that “weight” was a “real” quantity; that letter inquires about the “interaction problem.” Another woman argued that souls do not have a sex after she read this thinker’s work on “animal spirits.” This man died shortly after arriving in the court of Queen Kristina. Mary Astell argued for women’s education on account of this man’s idea that extended substances were separate from mental substances. Elizabeth of Bohemia critiqued this thinker’s namesake mind-body dualism. For 10 points, name this author of Meditations on First Philosophy whose Discourse on Method claims “I think therefore I am.” ","answer":"ANSWER: René Descartes (“day-CART”) [or Rene Des Cartes; accept words derived from his name, such as Cartesians or cartesiennes] (The first line is from Descartes’s correspondence with Elizabeth of Bohemia; the second is on Passions of the Soul; female followers of Descartes were known as cartesiennes.) <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"2. This character describes meeting the “head Llama” in Tibet and visiting the Khalifa at Khartoum in a short story about the card player Ronald Adair. This character, whose brother founded the Diogenes Club, helps a man who is paid to copy the encyclopedia. The captain of the Lone Star is sent the title objects by this character after the Ku Klux Klan murders John Openshaw in “The Five Orange Pips.” This character reveals he faked his death in “The Adventure of the Empty House” after battling Professor Moriarty at Reichenbach Falls in “The Final Problem.” For 10 points, Dr. John Watson is the companion of what detective created by Arthur Conan Doyle? ","answer":"ANSWER: Sherlock Holmes [accept either name] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"3. George Palmer translated this man’s endorsements of the angareion for use as the United States Postal Service’s unofficial motto. This man first described a rival kingdom’s demands of “earth and water,” and how their soldiers were marched to war between the two halves of Pythius’s son. The Muses lend their names to the nine divisions of this man’s most famous work, which was largely discovered as papyrus fragments at Oxyrhynchus. In that work, the Himalayan marmot may have inspired this man’s often-mocked descriptions of furry, gold-digging “ants.” Cicero called this man the “Father” of his discipline for his contemporary accounts of the Greco-Persian Wars. For 10 points, name this ancient Greek author of the Histories. ","answer":"ANSWER: Herodotus [or Herodotus of Halicarnassus] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"4. The nickname of a site at Mogao suggests that it contains a thousand depictions of this figure’s predecessors. This figure, who was often symbolically represented in early art with a pair of footprints, is depicted throughout the Longmen Grottoes. Sculptures of different predecessors to this figure hold different hand positions, or mudras, based on the direction they face at the site of Borobudur. The Ajanta caves depict this figure’s life in their paintings and rock-cuttings based on the Jataka tales. The Taliban destroyed massive sandstone statues of this figure at Bamiyan. For 10 points, what religious figure is often sculpted sitting in a lotus position as he meditates? ","answer":"ANSWER: Buddha [or Siddhartha Gautama; accept either part] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"5. A popular introductory textbook on the study of these constructs is commonly abbreviated “CLRS.” Formally, one of these constructs can be defined as a Turing machine that computes a function f. One paradigm of these things involves incrementally finding locally optimal choices and is exemplified by ones named for Prim and Kruskal; that is the “greedy” model of these constructs. The time and space complexity of these things can be expressed with big-O notation. Categories of these constructs include “randomized” and “divide-and-conquer.” For 10 points, name these step-by-step methods of solving problems, examples of which may “search” or “sort” data structures. ","answer":"ANSWER: algorithms [accept greedy algorithms] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"6. During a quarrel between this man’s sons, Zeus helped one of them by moving the sun backwards across the sky. In order to win his wife, this man convinced Myrtilus to replace bronze linchpins with ones made of wax. This man threw a rival off a cliff, bringing about a curse by which this man’s sons Atreus and Thyestes (“thee-ESS-teez”) destroyed his family. Oenomaus (“EE-no-MAY-uss”) was killed when his sabotaged chariot fell apart, letting this man beat him in a race. Hephaestus made an ivory shoulder for this man after Demeter accidentally ate his real one during a feast prepared from this man’s flesh by his father. For 10 points, name this husband of Hippodamia and son of Tantalus. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pelops <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"7. Description acceptable. The “Diary of Merer” was written by an official charged with procuring limestone for this task and is one of the world’s oldest surviving written texts. Jean-Pierre Houdin (“oo-DAN”) proposed the contested “internal ramp” hypothesis to explain how this task was accomplished. A method for accomplishing this task was developed to complete a project commissioned by Djoser (“JO-sir”) in Saqqara (“suh-KAR-uh”) and was designed by the chancellor and architect Imhotep. Contrary to Exodus-inspired myths, this task was likely accomplished by paid craftsman rather than Jewish slaves. For 10 points, name this process by which ancient Egyptians constructed a certain kind of monument at Giza. ","answer":"ANSWER: building the Pyramids [accept building the Great Pyramid or descriptive equivalents that indicate the construction of pyramids] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"8. A reference to a necklace of “topaz” was omitted when this author’s poem about “a pure white hind” was adapted as the poem “Whoso List to Hunt.” Although this author’s poem “If no love is, O God, what fele I so?” was translated by Chaucer, this author was first popularized in England through adaptations by the Earl of Surrey and Sir Thomas Wyatt. This author described being “caught” by a woman’s “lovely eyes” in a poem set on “the day the sun’s ray had turned pale.” This author wrote “You who hear the sound, in scattered rhymes” to begin his Il Canzoniere (“kont-sone-YAY-ray”), which contains many poems addressed to Laura. For 10 points, name this 14th century Italian poet who names a type of sonnet. ","answer":"ANSWER: Petrarch [or Francesco Petrarca; accept Petrarchan sonnet] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"9. The central figure of this painting is contrasted with a figure based on the model Laure in a Lorraine O’Grady essay on “Black female subjectivity,” which notes that woman’s role as both “Jezebel and Mammy.” The profession of this painting’s central subject is indicated by her pearl earrings, oriental shawl, and orchid in her hair. This painting’s subject stares directly at the viewer and is modeled on Victorine Meurent (“murr-ON”). The artist of this painting based it on Titian’s Venus of Urbino, but replaced that painting’s dog with a black cat. For 10 points, a black maid extends a bouquet to the title reclining nude woman in what painting by Édouard Manet? ","answer":"ANSWER: Olympia <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"0. In 2018, researchers at LLNL compressed this compound between two diamond fragments and then laser-shocked it to create the “superionic” form of this compound. Theodor Grotthuss developed the model of the proton-jumping mechanism for this compound. This compound is susceptible to dielectric heating because of its large dipole moment, which is why microwave ovens primarily target this molecule. This amphoteric molecule has high specific heat because it can form hydrogen bonds with itself. The Kelvin scale was previously defined by the triple point of this substance. For 10 points, identify this compound nicknamed the universal solvent. ","answer":"ANSWER: water [or H2O; or ice; accept superionic water] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"5. ","answer":"ANSWER: Eleanor Roosevelt [or Anna Eleanor Roosevelt; prompt on Roosevelt] <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"2. Within this field, left realists and right realists dispute Gottfredson and Hirschi’s (“HER-skee’s”) “general” social control theory. Alexandre Lacassagne (“la-ka-SAH-nyuh”) opposed the phrenology-obsessed “father” of this field who searched for “atavistic” features in subjects’ skull shapes; that man was Cesare (“CHEZ-ah-ray”) Lombroso. Durkheim’s idea of anomie (“ah-no-MEE”) inspired sociologist Robert Merton’s strain theory in this other field. Cesare Beccaria is best-known for work in this discipline, which is the subject of a Michel Foucault book that studies Jeremy Bentham’s Panopticon. Scholars in this field may research recidivism or “white collar” phenomena such as embezzlement and forgery. For 10 points, name this field that studies law-breaking acts. ","answer":"ANSWER: criminology [accept penology; accept criminal justice; prompt on criminal psychology; prompt on crime by asking “what is the field that studies crime?”] (The Foucault book is Discipline and Punish.) <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"3. A group of composers from this modern-day country who created the collection The Triumphs of Oriana were members of its namesake Madrigal School. A composer from this country used a “falling tear” motif in Lachrimae (“LACK-ree-MAY”), his most popular lute song. A ruler of this country granted two of its composers a 21-year monopoly on polyphonic music. John Dowland (“DOH-lind”) was born in this country, and another composer from here wrote the 40-part motet Spem in alium. An anthem originally from this country is often sung as the American patriotic song “My Country ’Tis Of Thee.” For 10 points, name this country in which Thomas Tallis and William Byrd composed for Anglican services. ","answer":"ANSWER: England [accept UK or United Kingdom or Great Britain; do not accept or prompt on “Scotland,” “Wales,” or “Ireland”] (The anthem is “God Save the Queen.”) <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"4. This author wrote about a woman who moves back to Paris after her husband learns about her affair with Dimitri Desjardins (“day-zhar-DAN”). In a short story by this author, a boy who begs his babysitter to put on a silver cocktail dress defines a compliment she heard earlier at the Mapparium as “loving someone you don’t know.” This author of “Sexy” created a character who is found holding the pages of “The Overcoat” after a train wreck. After a trip to the Sun Temple at Konarak, Mr. Kapasi saves Bobby from monkeys in a short story by this author. For 10 points, name this author who created Gogol Ganguli in The Namesake and wrote Interpreter of Maladies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jhumpa Lahiri [or Nilanjana Sudeshna Lahiri] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"5. An argument ironically named for this scientist centers around the spontaneous formation of a human brain due to random thermodynamic fluctuations. One of this man’s theorems was criticized for being in conflict with time reversal symmetry and can be derived from his “transport function.” The product of temperature and this man’s namesake constant appears in the denominator of thermodynamic beta. This man’s tombstone is engraved with the equation “S equals k log W,” a statistical definition of entropy that includes his namesake constant. For 10 points, name this pioneer of statistical mechanics who co-names a probability distribution with James Clerk Maxwell. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ludwig Boltzmann [or Ludwig Eduard Boltzmann] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"6. Description acceptable. Mentions of “physical attributes” were commonly reinterpreted as metaphors as part of a modification of this general belief that was held by all members of the Mu’tazila school. The 112th surah, Al-Ikhlāṣ, consists entirely of a short proclamation regarding this concept, which is not believed in by performers of shirk. When reciting the Shahada, before stating that “Muhammad is the messenger of God,” one first states this idea, which is also known as tawhid (“tao-HEED”). Early Arabs often worshipped a plethora of idols in opposition to this religious idea. For 10 points, a belief in what general idea lies at the center of Islam, in light of its status as a monotheistic religion? ","answer":"ANSWER: the oneness of God [or there is only one God; accept Allah in place of “God”; accept answers indicating that God is unique; accept monotheism until read, but prompt after; accept “there is no god except God”; accept tawhid until read, but prompt after; accept lā ’ilāha ’illā llāh; accept the first half/part of the Shahada until read] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"7. William Dalrymple’s 2019 book The Anarchy chronicles the “relentless rise” of this organization, whose actions were discussed in the Pratt-York opinion. This organization put a reward out for the head of Henry Every, sparking the first worldwide manhunt. One representative of this organization, Warren Hastings, reported on a 1770 famine caused by the policies of its official, Robert Clive. Unease over pre-greased rifle cartridges catalyzed the Sepoy Mutiny against this organization, which traded many commodities with Qing China and the Mughals. For 10 points, name this joint-stock company whose actions in India brought about the creation of the British Raj. ","answer":"ANSWER: British East India Company [or BEIC; accept Honorable East India Company or HEIC; accept John Company; accept Company Bahadur; prompt on East India Company] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"8. A man finds a refrigerator filled with the heads of these animals in a novel that features a character who eats these animals’ hearts and plans to use their souls to make a flute. At the end of a novel, a drunk one of these animals owned by Mr. Sneaze drowns in a barrel. A woman nicknamed for this animal taunts a man who hurt himself while jumping hurdles for his attraction to his friend Skipper. Nakata has the ability to talk to these animals in Kafka on the Shore. In a play titled for this animal, Gooper and Brick pretend that their father has a “spastic colon” instead of cancer. For 10 points, the Pollitt family features in a Tennessee Williams play titled for what type of animal on a Hot Tin Roof? ","answer":"ANSWER: cats [or felines or kittens or synonyms; accept I Am a Cat or Cat on a Hot Tin Roof] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"8. In October 2019, Jeremy Corbyn asked this leader “which clause in the bill” would protect the NHS from privatization. For 10 points, name this former Mayor of London who attempted to organize an October 31st leave from the EU as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom. ","answer":"ANSWER: Boris Johnson [or Alexander Boris de Pfeiffel Johnson] <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"0. An Olszewski (“ol-SHEFF-skee”) tube is a device designed to reverse the effects of this condition through destratification. A score of 50 to 70 on Carlson’s index indicates this condition, which can be controlled through the addition of calcium, aluminum, or iron salts. That aforementioned index for this condition is calculated from chlorophyll a concentration, total phosphorus, and Secchi (“SECK-ee”) disk visibility. This condition is most commonly caused by nonpoint source pollution, which increases turbidity and decreases light penetration, leading to the formation of hypoxic regions called dead zones. For 10 points, name this harmful phenomenon seen in bodies of water with excess nutrients that often leads to algal blooms. ","answer":"ANSWER: eutrophication (“yoo-tro-fih-KAY-shun”) [or word forms; accept hypereutrophication; accept algal blooms or phytoplankton blooms until read; prompt on dead zones or hypoxiac until read by asking “what causes them?”] <Biology> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name these animals. A “little” one of these animals “must think it queer” according to a speaker who describes woods as “lovely, dark and deep” and talks about “miles to go before I sleep.” ","answer":"ANSWER: horses [accept “She Had Some Horses” or “my little horse”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This author’s journey home on his horse after failing to make money for buying Christmas presents inspired his poem “Stopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening.” He wrote “The Road Not Taken.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert Frost [or Robert Lee Frost] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This poet wrote “Don’t let that horse / eat that violin” in a poem on Marc Chagall’s (“shuh-GALL’s”) creation of the painting The Horse With Violin In Mouth. This poet also wrote A Coney Island of the Mind. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lawrence Ferlinghetti [or Lawrence Monsanto Ferlinghetti] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this type of current, abbreviated DC, that is contrasted with alternating current. ","answer":"ANSWER: direct current "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This type of generator uses a moving belt to produce direct current. In a common science demonstration of static electricity, putting one’s hands on this device will cause their hair to stand up. ","answer":"ANSWER: Van de Graaff generator "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] A van de Graaff generator accumulates charge via this effect, in which rubbing two materials together causes them to become electrically charged. ","answer":"ANSWER: triboelectric effect <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this American economist whose namesake equation states the nominal interest rate is the sum of the real interest rate and the inflation rate. ","answer":"ANSWER: Irving Fisher "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Fisher was a proponent of this school, whose microeconomic ideas are fused with Keynesian (“CANE-zee-in”) macro in a namesake synthesis. It is named for updating the ideas of John Stuart Mill and Adam Smith. ","answer":"ANSWER: neoclassical economics "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The transition from classical to neoclassical economics was a “revolution” named for this adjective. This adjective is used to describe the change in utility from consuming an additional unit of a good or service. ","answer":"ANSWER: marginal revolution [or marginalism; accept marginal utility] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Two answers required. In 1903, construction began on a railway that would connect these two cities, in the German and Ottoman Empires respectively. The railway didn’t finish until 1940 but is often considered a factor in the outbreak of World War I. ","answer":"ANSWER: Berlin AND Baghdad [accept Berlin–Baghdad Railway; do not accept or prompt on individual answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This snowy, sparsely populated region names a massive railway system that was spearheaded by Tsar Alexander III, and connected Moscow to Vladivostok in the Far East. ","answer":"ANSWER: Siberia [or Sibír; accept Trans-Siberian Railroad] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] George Nagelmackers’s CIWL passenger car company operated this railway system that originally connected Paris to Constantinople. This system’s name derived from a broad, historical term for the East. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Orient Express [or the Express d’Orient] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Gauguin is best-known for his work done on this island, the setting of works like Spirit of the Dead Watching and Primitive Tales. He often depicted this island’s native women on beaches or surrounded by lush vegetation. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tahiti [prompt on French Polynesia] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Gauguin also spent much of his time in this region of France, especially its town of Pont-Aven (“pon-tah-VAWN”). He depicted the tall white bonnets of its peasant women’s traditional dress in paintings like Vision After the Sermon. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brittany [or Breton region; or Bretagne] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] In 1888, Gauguin stayed with this other artist at the Yellow House in Arles (“arl”), where scholars believe he may have cut off this artist’s ear. This Dutch-born artist painted The Starry Night. ","answer":"ANSWER: Vincent Van Gogh <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this island in the Gulf of Aden where early explorers believed red sap from “dragon blood” trees was cinnabar. Hadibu is home to the only airport on this island. ","answer":"ANSWER: Soqotra [or Socotra] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The Avenue of the Baobabs lines a road leading to this island country’s city of Morondava. This largest island in the Indian Ocean speaks a Malayo-Polynesian language in its capital of Antananarivo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Madagascar [or Madagasikara; accept Repoblikan’i Madagasikara or the Republic of Madagascar] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] In the Maldives, blocks from massive coral reefs were used to construct one of these buildings titled Hukuru. In September 2019, renovations to one of these non-Christian buildings in Mayotte was dubbed the sister project to the Notre-Dame renovations. ","answer":"ANSWER: mosque [or masjid; accept Malé Friday Mosque] <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this novel that also inspired a parody in which the female heroine tricks Squire Booby into marriage. Both parodies mock the ideals presented in this Samuel Richardson novel, subtitled “Virtue Rewarded.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Pamela [or Pamela; or, Virtue Rewarded] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This author of Shamela frequently digressed while chronicling the life of a “foundling” in his novel Tom Jones. ","answer":"ANSWER: Henry Fielding "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Pamela and Shamela both have this surname. A Henry Fielding novel written “in imitation of the manner of Cervantes” imagines Pamela’s brother of this surname, who is mentored by Abraham Adams. ","answer":"ANSWER: Andrews [accept Joseph Andrews] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: New Orleans "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This Massachusetts general and future radical Republican became the first military governor of New Orleans. He sparked scandal by ordering that New Orleans women who disrespected Union troops should be given as little respect as prostitutes. ","answer":"ANSWER: Benjamin Butler "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"1. ","answer":"ANSWER: P. G. T. Beauregard [or Pierre Gustave Toutant-Beauregard] <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name these proteins that comprise around 80% of the protein content in cow’s milk. ","answer":"ANSWER: casein (“KAY-seen”) [or paracasein; or caseinogen] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Due to its protein-rich nature, non-fat milk often functions as a blocking agent in this biological technique used to detect and analyze the expression of proteins separated by gel electrophoresis. ","answer":"ANSWER: western blot [prompt on blotting] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] In addition to proteins, milk contains carbohydrates such as this sugar. People with a mutation in the MCM6 gene develop an “intolerance” for this disaccharide. ","answer":"ANSWER: lactose <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Describing many native African religions, this term was held by Edward Tylor to be the developmental phase for all religions. This term, from the Latin for “breath,” is the belief that all objects and phenomena possess a spirit or soul. ","answer":"ANSWER: animism [or word forms, such as animistic religions; prompt on fetishism or totemism or pantheism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] African faiths also often feature this practice, which babalawos perform by reading kola nuts on a wooden tray. In ancient China, “oracle bones” were used for this practice, which may be performed by reading tarot (“TAIR-oh”) cards. ","answer":"ANSWER: divination [or word forms, such as divining; accept Ifá; accept descriptive answers such as prophecy, fortune-telling, or telling the future] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The Bwa of Burkina Faso are known for making the tall nwantaytay type of these objects, which are often used in the ancestor venerating egungun festival. Dogon dance societies, or awa, are centered around these objects. ","answer":"ANSWER: masks [prompt on costumes] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this musician who collaborated with Yehudi Menuhin (“yeh-HOO-dee MEN-yoo-in”) on two albums titled East Meets West. This composer also wrote the music for the Apu Trilogy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ravi Shankar "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Long after meeting through the Asian Music Circle, Ravi Shankar collaborated with a member of this musical group on the album Chants of India. That man, George Harrison, switched to playing sitar for this band’s 1965 track “Norwegian Wood” for their album Rubber Soul. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Beatles "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Indian conductor Zubin Mehta is the only Conductor Emeritus of this city’s premier orchestra. Esa-Pekka Salonen and Gustavo Dudamel conducted that orchestra in this city’s Walt Disney Concert Hall. ","answer":"ANSWER: Los Angeles [or LA; accept Los Angeles Philharmonic, LA Phil, or LAP] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this leader who imprisoned many political opponents on the island of Goli Otok. This first Chairperson of the Non-Aligned Movement split with Stalin over matters such as the Hungarian Revolution. ","answer":"ANSWER: Josip Broz Tito [or Josip Broz] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Tito led this Central European country, which would eventually break up into multiple successor states including Serbia and Montenegro, Bosnia and Herzegovina, and Croatia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yugoslavia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] As leader of the Partisan resistance during World War II, Tito strongly opposed the Axis collaboration of this other Yugoslavian royalist faction, led by Draža Mihailović. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Chetnik movement [or Chetniks; accept Ravna Gora Movement; accept Yugoslav Army in the Homeland] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this servant who worries his employers when he uses the bakkie (“back-ee”) without their permission. This character brings those employers to his village during a civil war. ","answer":"ANSWER: July "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This author of The Conservationist wrote about Bam and Maureen Smales fleeing to their servant’s village in her novel July’s People. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nadine Gordimer "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The fictional civil war in July’s People depicts the downfall of apartheid in this home country of Gordimer. ","answer":"ANSWER: South Africa [or Republic of South Africa] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this view. George Berkeley’s (“BARK-lee’s”) “immaterialism” is another variant of this position, which holds that only minds and mental constructs truly exist. ","answer":"ANSWER: subjective idealism [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Samuel Johnson made the first argumentum ad lapidem by performing this specific action and proclaiming “I refute it thus” when discussing Berkeley’s “ingenious sophistry to prove the non-existence of matter.” ","answer":"ANSWER: kicking a rock [or equivalents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Berkeley attacked the fluxions used by this other thinker as “ghosts of departed quantities.” Berkeley’s De motu opposes the notions of absolute space and time argued in this physicist’s Principia Mathematica. ","answer":"ANSWER: Issac Newton <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this substance contained in aquifers. The distribution of this substance is studied in hydrogeology. ","answer":"ANSWER: groundwater "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The ability of groundwater to flow through an aquifer can be described by this law. This law establishes a proportional relationship between a fluid’s flow rate and its viscosity, the medium’s permeability, and the pressure drop over a given distance. ","answer":"ANSWER: Darcy’s law [do not accept or prompt on “Darcy–Weisbach equation”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The groundwater flow equation is formulated by combining Darcy’s law with this other law. This law implies that its namesake quantity can be neither created nor destroyed. ","answer":"ANSWER: law of conservation of mass [or mass conservation; do not accept or prompt on “law of conservation of matter”] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this performing arts center on Bennelong Point. Ove Arup engineered the fourteen shells that resemble “white sails” atop this opera house designed by Jørn Utzon (“YURN OOT-sun”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Sydney Opera House "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] A proscenium theater in the Sydney Opera House is named for this Australian-born Dame. This six-foot-tall soprano was nicknamed “La Stupenda” for her coloratura technique. ","answer":"ANSWER: Joan Sutherland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Due in part to the difficulty of finding partners taller than her, this singer toured with Sutherland in the early ’60s. With José Carreras and Placido Domingo, he formed the Three Tenors. ","answer":"ANSWER: Luciano Pavarotti <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this character who plays a “wild dance” on the piano before shooting herself in the play titled for her. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hedda Gabler [accept either name] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Hedda Gabler is the title character of a play by this Norwegian author of A Doll’s House. ","answer":"ANSWER: Henrik Ibsen "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Ibsen was given a front-row seat when attending a lecture by this younger author, who proceeded to insult Ibsen for writing shallow social drama with an “indefensibly coarse and artificial psychology.” This fellow Norwegian wrote about a man who “wandered about and starved in Christiania” in his novel Hunger. ","answer":"ANSWER: Knut Hamsun [or Knut Pedersen] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this technique also used in the Castner–Kellner process. Faraday’s Laws give the mass of the result of this process. ","answer":"ANSWER: electrolysis "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The Downs cell uses electrolysis to produce sodium at the cathode and this gaseous element at the anode. Along with sodium, this element is found in table salt. ","answer":"ANSWER: chlorine [or Cl] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] About 4% of the commercial production of this element is created through electrolysis. Along with carbon dioxide and carbon monoxide, this element is found in syngas (“sin-gas”). ","answer":"ANSWER: hydrogen [or H or H2] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Give the European name for this isolated Pacific island whose population was annihilated in the late 19th century. This island’s huge moai statues are sometimes referred to as its namesake heads. ","answer":"ANSWER: Easter Island "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This indigenous ethnic group of Easter Island wrote in rongorongo and built the island’s moai. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rapa Nui "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The Rapa Nui’s moai-centered religion either coexisted with or was supplanted by the worship of this creator deity who sponsored the island’s birdman cult. ","answer":"ANSWER: Makemake (“MA-kay-MA-kay”) <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this Sumerian goddess of beauty and fertility. In a poem, this goddess descends to the underworld and is forced to relinquish a garment of clothing at each of its seven gates. ","answer":"ANSWER: Inanna [accept Ishtar] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Ereshkigal turns Inanna into a rotting corpse, but she is rescued and revived by two gallu created by this deity. This Sumerian god of freshwater and wisdom is also the father of Marduk. ","answer":"ANSWER: Enki [accept Ea; do not accept “Enkidu”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Inanna travels to the underworld for the funeral of Ereshkigal’s husband, Gugalanna, who had been killed by Enkidu and this hero. This king of Uruk searches for immortality in his namesake epic. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gilgamesh [or Gilgames or Bilgamesh or Bilgames] <Mythology>"}]
